Nicholas Bauer Level: Consultant

Email: Bauer Nicholas@bah.com

(571) 471-0535: Cell (571) 346-8472: Work Clearance: N/A but Eligible Residence: Sterling, Virginia Willing to Relocate: Locally % Willing to Travel: 60% Last update: 10/29/2019

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Quick-learner that has effective communication skills who takes pride in his work. Works well with a team or independently and comfortable with decision-making. Keeps team members on task, and on time while motivating and inspiring them to do their best work. Experienced in Microservice-based architecture, algorithmic applications, and object-oriented programming: developing, testing and debugging code. Has experience using Git & GitHub for version control. Has developed strong analytical skills in many types of data analysis (linear regression, predictive modeling etc.): interpreting data and analyzing results for presentation in a clear, concise manner. Has experience using data visualization tools such as Tableau, R & SAS. Has gained proficiency in Microsoft programs.

EDUCATION

BS Mathematics, Radford University, 2019

- Concentrations: Applied Mathematics, Statistics
- Minors: Computer Science, Information Systems

COMPETENCIES (SCHOOL RELATED EXPERIENCE)

- Software Development (2.5 yrs)
- Database Management Systems (1 yr)
- Software Engineering (2.5 yrs)

- Data Analysis (2 yrs)
- Web Software Development (2.5 yrs)

CERTIFICATIONS

N/A

SUMMARY OF SKILLS, TOOLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES:

Programming Languages: Java (2.5 yrs), HTML (2.5yrs), CSS (2.5 yrs), SQL (1 yr), Maple (1 yr), MATLAB (1 yr), SAS (1 yr), R (.5 yrs), JMP (.5 yrs), Python (.5 yrs), PHP (.5 yrs), Javascript (.5 yrs), XML (.5 yrs)

Databases: MySQL (1 yr), HSQL (.5 yrs)

Frameworks: Node.js (1 yr), React.js (.5 yrs.), Express (.5 yrs), Spring Boot (.5 yrs) **Operating Systems:** Windows (10 yrs), Mac OS (5 yrs), Unix (2 yrs), Linux (.5 yrs)

EXPERIENCE

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc., Technologist

7/2019 - Present

Herndon, VA

- New Hire, (Jr. Full Stack Developer)
- Starting Date 7/29/2019

Modern Software Development Course

- Completed Booz Allen's Internal Modern SD Course developed Spring Boot RESTful API's
- Topics covered: Microservice-based architectures, Git/Github, Spring Framework, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JWT XML, Maven/Gradle, JUnit, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Jaeger, Prometheus SIG Training
 - Spring Framework, currently pursuing AWS Associate Developer Certification

Radford University (School Projects)

8/2014 - 5/2019

Radford, VA

- Completed many Java Projects during the course of my studies: Pong, Blackjack, Live-Data Information apps implementing JSON API's (Stock Data & Live Weather Updates)
- Developed app that records network download speed over time and stores data in a MySQL DB
- Various NodeJs Web Applications

Signs and Wonders, Data Entry

5/2018 - 9/2018

Herndon, VA

- Creating and maintaining databases using Microsoft Excel
- Keeping data well organized, easy to read, and updating data when necessary